都不记得还有你这号人
I don't remember you.
- 重要吗？ - 不重要
- Does it matter? - No.
挺识相的 霍夫曼
Smart decision, Hoffman.
我看你 挺普通的
I look at you, and you seem almost normal.
有点趾高气昂 但普通
Arrogant but normal.
本以为能见到邪恶的真面目
I thought I'd get to see what evil really looked like...
结果你和普通人没什么两样
but you just look like everyone else.
说完了吧？我可以走了吧？
Is that it? Can I go now?
我拿走的全都在这儿了
This is everything that I took from you.
我的代理会留一份用作保险
My representatives will keep one safety copy.
要是那帮打手还跟着我
If your thugs follow me out of here,
要是我出了事
if anything happens to me,
备份就会交给警方
that copy goes to law enforcement...
我懂 我懂
I know how this works.
还得拍张照
I need to take a picture.
合影
Of us.
来 老朋友
Two old buddies.
可得裱起来
Hope you frame it.
祝你一帆风顺
Good luck with your new life,
霍夫曼先生
Mr. Hoffman.
多谢等候
Thanks for waiting.
往上城开 等会儿告诉你在哪儿下
Uptown, please. I'll tell you where in a minute.
专属答录信箱 信箱482
Special answering service, inbox 482.
一条新留言
One new message.
那份报告拿回了
We have the report back.
你的款也付清了
You've been paid for your services.
只要霍夫曼守约 事情就到此为止
As long as Hoffman sticks to his side of the deal, we're done.
顺便转达下我老板的问候
And by the way, a message from my boss.
你个寄生的渣虫
You're parasitic scum.
我是霍夫曼
Hoffman here.
昨晚和他见面了 我已按指示交还文件
He showed last night. I handed over the documents
还坐火车去了波基普西
and took the train to Poughkeepsie as instructed.
希望你那份备份
I hope the safety copy is enough
能让奥蒂莫制药别再来找咱们麻烦
to keep Optimo off my back and yours.
你的那半已经寄了
I sent the other half of the money to the address you provided.
没想到和解款这么多
I wasn't expecting so much myself.
我还以为他们该付给你的钱也给我了 谢谢了
I thought that would go for your fee. Thank you.
他们真会守约吗？
Are they gonna play fair?
格兰特女士
Ms. Grant?
你好 我是朱莉
Hi. I'm Julie.
- 你好 - 莫雷尔律师现在可以见您了
- Hi. - Mr. Morel will see you now.
谢谢
Thank you.
我在团队里
I was in a team,
负责用精确育种
uh, developing a new wheat strain
开发一种抗虫害的新小麦品种
resistant to insect predation through precision breeding.
有点像基因改造
It's... It's like genetic modification,
不过是靠自然杂交
only it's using natural processes,
所以不受那类严格监管
so it's not subject to the same tight regulation.
总之
Anyway.
我们进展不错
We were making progress,
但后来发现其对人类食物链可能有害
but we were noticing possible human food-chain issues.
有封邮件抄送给我
Um, and then I was CC'ed on an e-mail chain
附件里有一份食品安全评估
where one of the attachments was a food safety assessment
指出产品有明显的不良反应
showing significant side effects.
我向高层反映后
When I raised this issue with senior management,
他们说我理解错了
um, they told me that I'd seen the data out of context
叫我别担心
and not to worry.
但很快我被调走了
But then, um, soon, I was transferred
调到曼哈顿来了
to another department here in Manhattan.
做文职和数据工作
Office work, data assessment.
两个月后
Um, and then, two months later,
因为小小的打卡疏忽 他们就把我开了
I was dismissed on a minor time card violation,
现在还对我不断地骚扰
and now I'm being subjected to escalating harassment.
呃...
Uh...
深表同情 格兰特女士
I'm sorry to hear that, Ms. Grant.
他们为什么这样对您？
Why do you think this is happening?
我觉得...
I felt, um...
我觉得有责任把那份评估报告带走留证
Well, I felt I had a duty to take a copy of the food safety assessment as evidence.
您从前雇主那偷了文件？
You stole documents from your former employers?
偷？ 这能叫偷？
Is that... Is that stealing?
请问为什么找我们律所处理？
May I ask why you decided to discuss this issue with our firm?
有人介绍的
I followed a recommendation.
请问谁介绍的？
May I ask from whom?
一个朋友 不方便透露
A friend. It wouldn't be appropriate to say who.
格兰特女士 可以理解您的初衷
Ms. Grant, I commend you on your intentions here,
但我们早已不接这类案子
but we're no longer looking for this type of business.
有很多更专业的机构 能帮助你揭发内幕
Uh, there are a number of highly regarded whistleblower support organizations
非常专业...
much better prepared...
不 我不是要揭发
No. It's not whistle blowing support I need.
恰恰相反
It's the opposite.
我只想把文件都还回去
I just want to give everything back
保证守口如瓶 回到正常生活
and promise to keep my mouth shut and get on with my life.
请帮帮我 帮帮我
Please. Please.
有谁能帮我吗？
Is there anyone who can help me?
可以找正规的专业机构 但...
Well, as I said, there are official channels, but, uh...
好吧...
Look, um...
我们也会把人介绍给非正式渠道
There are unofficial ones we've referred people to in the past.
给你这个号码 也许能帮上忙
Just take this number, and maybe they can help you.
这是谁？
Who is he?
没见过他 也可能是她 或者一群人
I've never met him, or her or they.
匿名才是重点 那只是个传话服务
That's kind of the point. It's a messaging service.
他们会回电
They call you back...
也可能不回
or they don't.
把实情电话里讲清楚
Just be honest about your situation.
都准备好了
You are all set.
楼下大堂24小时有人 有需要随时打电话
The lobby's attended 24 hours a day. Call if you need anything.
多谢这么快就安排好了
Thanks for doing this on short notice.
该做的 住得舒心
That's what we do. Enjoy your stay.
大家好 我叫沃什 我有酒瘾
Hey, I'm Wash, and I'm an alcoholic.
- 你好 沃什 - 欢迎你
- Hi, Wash. - Hi, Wash.
我戒酒已有九年零九个月了
I've been sober nine years, nine months.
但...
And...
但最近特难熬
It's been even more of a struggle recently
老诱因又来了
because there's why I drank in the first place,
加上工作中乱七八糟的事
and then there's me doing what I do.
毕竟我以当警察为荣
'Cause I'm proud of serving on the force.
我也尽量按规矩办事
And I stay on the up and up.
差不多是这样
Pretty much.
但...
But, um...
我每天看到同事们那样做事儿...
What I see on the daily, amongst my fellow officers...
真 真无语
I... I... I don't know.
两条新留言
Two new messages.
”我是霍夫曼 一切安好”
Hoffman here. All right.
“我叫莎拉·格兰特
My name is Sarah Grant.
“曾在一家生物科技公司任职科学家
Um, I was a scientist working at a bio tech company,
“是赛博育种
Cybo Sementis.
“我 我手里有些资料
I... I'm in possession of materials
“能证明他们掩盖违法行为
which are evidence of an unlawful cover-up.
“我本来想公之于众 现在反悔了
I was gonna go public, but I changed my mind.
“告诉我该怎么办 我会全力配合
I don't know how this works, but I'll do whatever is necessary.
“我的电话是693-824-4011”
My number is 693-824-4011.
我们很荣幸获得兰辛奖
We are delighted to be the recipients of the Lansing Award.
这项研究有望大幅提升粮食产量
This research has the potential to revolutionize grain yields,
对发展中国家意义重大
particularly in developing countries, where they need it,
还能减少农药使用
lowering reliance on pesticides.
有了这笔资助
And with this grant,
真心希望能创造价值
we really hope to make a difference.
您好 这是大都会传呼中心
Hello. This is the Tri-State Relay Service.
嗯 请讲
Yes. Hello.
某人使用传呼跟您通话
A person is calling through relay service.
您接过传呼电话吗？
Have you received a relay call before?
没有吧
I don't think so.
来电者可能有听力障碍
The person who has called you is likely to be deaf or hard of hearing.
对方会打字 我负责念给您听
The caller will type their conversation, and I'll read it to you.
您说的话我会以文字回传
When it's your turn, I'll type everything you say.
请直接讲话 要我发回复时
Speak directly to the caller and say, "Go ahead,"
请说「请传达」
when you're ready for a response.
本通话不录音 严格保密
No calls are recorded, and everything you say is confidential.
通话马上开始 请稍等
One moment for your call to begin.
“您叫莎拉·伊丽莎白·格兰特”
"You are Sarah Elizabeth Grant.
“社保号是958-00-4493”
Your Social Security number is 958-00-4493."
“曾受雇于赛博育种研究所”
"You were employed by Cybo Sementis Research Institutes,
“公司税号99-0890590 地点在圣路易斯 对吗？”
tax ID 99-0890590, based in St. Louis. Is that correct?"
对
Yes.
说完请说「请传达」
If finished, please respond with "Go ahead."
抱歉 抱歉 请传达
Oh, I'm sorry. I'm sorry. I'm sorry. Go ahead.
“请把情况说明一下”
"Please explain your situation."
我在一个项目里 研究抗虫小麦新品种
I was in a research group developing a new strain of insect-resistant wheat.
有份食品安全报告出来
Um, a food-safety report came back
指出严重的不良反应
with disturbing data about side effects.
我向上级报告了
I told my bosses.
结果我被调走
Next thing I knew, I'd been reassigned
后来干脆被开除了
and later dismissed.
新品种照常生产
Production of the new strain has gone ahead,
报告被压了下去
but these findings have been suppressed.
我设法留了份报告副本
Um, but I was able to get a copy of that food safety report out of the building.
请传达
Go ahead.
“什么不良反应？”
"You mention side effects."
个别案例里有
In a small number of cases,
严重过敏反应 乃至过敏性休克
there were extreme allergies, anaphylaxis.
长期观察显示 结肠憩室炎
And in longer-term cases, diverticulitis
以及癌症的发生率远高于基线
and cancer well above base rate.
据估计 一旦全球上市后
They project massive worldwide sales.
成千上万的人会受影响
Thousands of people will be affected.
没有这份报告
But without the information I have,
就不可能把病因追溯到食品上
it will be impossible to trace it back to the food people have eaten.
“您的文件能证明他们的不法行为吗？”
"Would you say this document contains clear evidence of malfeasance?"
比起他们造假的报告 这份是铁证如山
Compared to the fraudulent version of their report, yes.
请传达
Go ahead.
“他们给钱收买您吗？”
"Did they offer you a cash settlement in exchange for your silence?"
起初他们想 但我没接受
Um, initially, yes, but I wasn't interested.
我想揭发真相
I wanted to do the right thing.
然后他们开始威胁我
But then the intimidation started.
昨晚还烧了我的车
Last night, they set my car on fire.
请传达
Go ahead.
“报警了吗？”
"Are the police involved?"
车被拖走当证物
They towed the car away as evidence,
我还没让警方介入 请传达
but I haven't involved them. Go ahead.
“那就别 事发地点是翠贝卡区钱伯斯街200号吗？”
"Don't. Was this at 200 Chambers Street in Tribeca?"
对
Yes.
因为威胁我已经搬走了
But I've moved now because of the threats.
请传达
Go ahead.
“买个一次性手机”
"Buy a prepaid cellphone,
“关机 到公共场所再开机”
keep it switched off till you get to a public place,
“然后留言告诉我您的新号码”
then leave a message with your new number,
“新住址和细节”
"new address, and any further details."
楼下停着辆大面包
There's a van parked out front.
我觉得他们在监视我 请传达
I think they're watching me. Go ahead.
“他们可能在窃听”
"They may be tapping this call.
“今后只用新手机联系”
In the future, only use your new phone."
来电者已挂断
Your caller has hung up.
感谢使用大都会传呼 祝您晚上愉快
Thank you for using the Tri-State Relay Service. Have a wonderful night.
“楼下停着辆大面包”
There's a van parked out front.
“我觉得他们在监视我 请传达”
I think they're watching me. Go ahead.
找到了 扬克斯东大道339号
Okay. 339 East Avenue, Yonkers, New York.
“今后只用新手机联系”
"Only use your new phone."
夜班外勤 谁来？
Night shift. Who's coming?
《1990年美国残疾人法》第225条规定
The Americans with Disabilities Act of 1990, Section 225,
传话通讯运营方不得泄露
prohibits relay operators from disclosing the content
任何传呼通话的内容
of any relayed conversation
也不得在通话结束后
and from keeping records of the content
保存通话内容的记录
of any such conversation beyond the duration of the call.
行 行 不想申请搜查令把事闹大 你想吗？
Okay. Okay. I don't want to go and get a warrant. Do you?
- 不想 - 你刚才说你是哪个部门的？
- No. - Where'd you say you're from?
- 财政部 - 调查挪用公款
- Treasury Department. - Misappropriations.
好 哪怕有搜查令也无济于事
Okay. Even with a warrant, there'd be nothing to search.
我们不留通话记录
We don't keep records of our logs,
也不记通话来源去向
where they're coming from, or where they're going to.
我是莎拉·格兰特
This is Sarah Grant.
我的新号码是718-493-7071
Um, my new number is 718-493-7071.
现在住在 华盛顿街1500号 2Q公寓 邮编10006
1500 Washington Street, apartment 2Q, uh, 10006.
公司眼看就要以
The company is on the verge of being acquired
32亿美元被收购了
based on an estimated value of $3.2 billion,
下周证监会就会把这事敲定
which will be confirmed at an SEC filing next week.
我掌握的信息要是被曝光 交易就会泡汤
If the information I had went public, it would break that deal.
他们会不择手段阻止我
They are highly incentivized to prevent that,
所以我很害怕
which is why I'm scared.
- 喂 - 有人使用传呼跟您通话
- Hello. - A person is calling you through Relay Service.
您接过传呼电话吗？
Have you received a relay call before?
接过 请传达
Yes. Go ahead.
“我们了解了您的情况 方案如下”
"After reviewing your situation, here's the deal."
“帮您把文件交回 还留筹码来保护您”
We can help you return the documents whilst maintaining leverage to protect you.
“先付五万美元押金”
We require a $50,000 deposit up front.
“押金最后从和解款中退给您”
This will be returned to you from money we recover during the negotiation process.
“您是否能负担这笔费用？”
"Can you afford this?"
可以 请传达
Yes. Go ahead.
“接下来几天”
"Over the next few days,"
“您会收到些看似奇怪的要求”
you will receive some strange requests
“目的是摸清对手”
designed to show us what we're up against.
“不管要求多奇怪都请照做”
Please follow all instructions no matter how odd.
“今后每次通话都要对暗号”
In the future, we will use a passcode before each conversation.
“我们会问「信用卡还是借记卡」”
We will say, 'Credit or debit?'
“您回答「支票」 明白吗？”
You will say, 'Check.' Understood?"
明白
Understood.
哪位？
Who is it?
有您快递
Package for you.
谢谢
Thanks.
- 喂 - 大都会传呼中心
- Hello. - Tri-State Relay Service.
您接过传呼电话吗？
Have you received a relay call before?
接过 请传达
Yes. Go ahead.
“信用卡还是借记卡”
Credit or debit?
支票 请传达
Check. Go ahead.
“明早先坐纽瓦克10:05的航班飞匹兹堡”
"Tomorrow morning, take the 10:05 flight from Newark to Pittsburgh,
“然后在11:50转飞亚特兰大”
then the 11:50 to Atlanta.
“别带这部手机”
Do not take this phone with you.
“带上装押金和报告的信封”
Take the packages with our deposit
“还有您收到的那台红标手机”
and the report and the red-marked phone you were sent.
“没到匹兹堡登机口前别开机”
"Do not turn it on until you are at your gate in Pittsburgh."
来电者已挂断
Your caller has hung up.
传呼员 我忘了点事 能回拨吗？
Operator, I forgot something. Can I call back?
对方设置了禁止回拨
The caller has placed a no-callback request on this line.
抱歉 女士
Sorry, ma'am.
下一位
Next.
- 谢谢惠顾 - 太感谢啦
- Thank you. - Thank you so much.
欢迎光临
Hello.
温馨提示
This is a preboarding announcement
飞往亚特兰大的8917航班 预计满座
for Flight 8917 to Atlanta. we are expecting a full flight today,
如需在登机口托运行李 请尽快
so if you'd like to gate-check your bag, please see us at the desk.
您好
Hello.
我在B17登机口那边捡到个包
I found this bag up by Gate B17.
是在洗手间旁吧？
Let me guess. Near the bathroom?
- 对 你怎么知道 - 这事常有
- Yeah. How did you know? - Happens all the time.
上面写着“莎拉·格兰特”
It says "Sarah Grant" on it.
- 好 我来处理 - 麻烦了
- Okay. I'll take it from here. - Okay. Good luck.
喂
Hello?
“信用卡还...”
Credit or...
支票
Check.
请传达
Go ahead.
“您现在在哪里？”
"Where are you now?"
在登机口
At the gate.
马上要登机了
Um, we're about to board.
下一步呢 请传达
Um, what should I do? Go ahead.
“您的包在身边吧？”
"Do you have the packages?"
- 在 请传达 - “那就好”
- Yes. Go ahead. - "Good."
乘客莎拉·格兰特 请到失物招领处
Passenger Sarah Grant, please come to the Lost-property counter.
Passenger Sarah Grant. Lost-property counter.
我去看下
I'm gonna check it out.
“不要理会一切广播 耐心等指示”
"Ignore everything else and await instructions."
乘客莎拉·格兰特 请到失物招领处
Passenger Sarah Grant, please come to the Lost-property counter.
“去D廊的邮局 把两个信封都寄了”
"Go to the post office in concourse D and mail both packages."
“稍后再联系”
"We will call you back."
您好先生 有事吗？
Sir, may I help you with something?
乘客莎拉·格兰特 请立刻到A29登机口登机
Passenger Sarah Grant, please report to Gate A29.
别想让我再坐你们的飞机了
I'm never flying your airline again.
- 她人呢？ - 没见到
- Where is she? - No-show.
广播一直叫她 但她没来
They keep calling her name. She didn't show up.
要分开找吗？如果那群家伙跟着来了
Wanna do another lap? If they're following her,
肯定就在附近
they gotta be in here somewhere.
最后通知 8317航班飞往亚特兰大正在关舱
Final call for Grant, for Flight 8317 to Atlanta.
乘客莎拉·格兰特 请速到登机口
Passenger Sarah Grant. Final call for Atlanta.
没人跟着她
They're not following her.
这话啥意思？
What do you mean?
我们暴露了
We're made.
- 你在哪里？- 你猜不到的
- Where are you? - You won't believe it,
她在邮局窗口
but she's at the post office.
明白
Okay.
这个寄到俄克拉荷马州诺曼市 邮编73019
And this one is Norman, Oklahoma, 73019.
有液体 易碎 或危险品吗？
Anything liquid, fragile, hazardous?
没有
No.
您的运单号在这里
So, your tracking numbers are right here.
欢迎在这里给个好评
And if you wanna fill out a survey, it's right there.
- 嗯 - 好评哦
- Okay. - Okay?
- 谢谢 - 谢谢您
- Thanks. - Thank you.
运单号是840-59-70-0233803
So, the tracking number is 840-59-70-0233803.
来复盘下 我们学到了什么？
Okay. So, what can we learn?
机场那套布得真巧 环环相扣
Hm? 'Cause the airport security thing, it was smart, it was tight.
干嘛要大费周折去匹兹堡？
Why send us all the way to Pittsburgh?
2001年后运输安全管理局几乎
Since 2001, the TSA has closed over 113 airport branches
关掉了所有机场邮局
of the United States Post Office.
只有匹兹堡的还在安检后
The only one remaining inside security is Pittsburgh.
好 所以分开寄到了两个信箱
All right. So, there's two P.O. Box addresses.
把我们分开 逼我们不停奔波
Split us up and keep us running.
这招真是机灵到家了
Looks like it's fucking working.
对 对
Yep. Yep.
你猜我怎么看？
You know what I think?
我喜欢这单
I think I like this one.
乌拉
Hoorah.
遇到个狡猾的对手
They're smarter than we thought.
嘿 把运单号给我下
Hey, do you have those tracking numbers for me?
- 给你 - 查下我们去哪儿奔波
- There you go. - Let's see where we're going.
支票 请传达
Check. Go ahead.
“干得好 请确认文件已经完整寄出”
"Good job. Please confirm that you've sent all the documents
- “没有多余副本” - 确认
- and have no further copies." - I confirm.
那 那帮人今天在机场吗？请传达
Were... Were they there today at the airport? Go ahead.
“在”
"Yes."
那你们也在那儿吗？请传达
So, you were, too? Go ahead.
“不要主动联系那帮人”
"Do not contact them yourself."
“他们找您也别回应”
Do not respond if they contact you.
“他们可能恐吓您 也可能想谈交易易”
They may try to scare you, and they may try to make a deal.
“我是您唯一的出路”
But this is the only deal.
“包裹一到 我们会跟他们谈判”
Once the packages arrive, we will make them an offer.
“那之后您要见面他们一次 把东西还回去”
"You're going to meet them once to make the return yourself."
非得去吗？请传达
Do I have to? Go ahead.
“到那时 您就有足够的筹码”
"By then, you will have all the leverage you need."
你们一起去吗？请传达
And you'll be there? Go ahead.
“您永远见不到我们 我们不是保镖”
"You will never meet us. We are not bodyguards."
“我们是中介”
We are intermediaries.
“我们会安排归还原件事宜”
We will broker a deal to return the original documents
“同时留一份备份做保险”
and retain one safety copy
“确保赛博育种遵守协议”
to make sure Cybo Sementis sticks to that deal.
“按我们的指示做 您会被保护”
Follow our instructions, and you will be protected.
“不按的话 我们就不管 后果自负”
"But if you don't, you will put yourself in danger and we will walk away."
我明白 请传达
I understand. Go ahead.
“您的旧手机已被攻破”
"Your old phone will be compromised."
“把它泡在盐水报废”
Put it in a pan of salt water.
“改用这部”
"Use this one now."
来电者已挂断 感谢使用大都会传呼
Your caller has hung up. Thank you for using the Tri-State Relay Service.
祝您晚上愉快
Have a wonderful night.
喂 摄像头我装好了
Hey. Yeah. I got a camera in position.
但一无所获
But I don't got nothing.
你呢？密歇根那边怎样？
What about you? How's Michigan treating you?
我猜比你那鸟不拉屎的地方好
I'm guessing better than Bumfuck, Oklahoma.
- 哈哈 可不是么 - 这儿环境可好了
- Damn. - It's really pretty.
- 您好 - 嗨 我来替朋友阿奇取个邮件
- Hi. - Hi. I wanna pick up a package for my friend Archie.
521号信箱
He's got box 521.
我有运单号 但钥匙忘带了
I have the tracking number, but I forgot the key.
能麻烦帮我拿一下吗？
Would you be able just to grab it for me?
抱歉 女士 我们有规定
Well, I'm afraid, ma'am, that regulations do not permit me
不能帮客户开信箱
to open mailboxes for our clients.
- 哦 不会吧 - 没办法
- Oh, no. Really? - Sorry.
都怪我 我不该忘带那破钥匙
It's my fault. Should've remembered the darn key.
嗯
Yeah.
只 只是我家狗病得很重
Just... My dog is really sick.
- 哦 - 现在脑袋一片浆糊
- Oh. - Yeah. My head is a mess.
对 对不起
I... I'm sorry.
- 是啊 挺遗憾的 - 嗯
- Well, that's a shame, ma'am. - Yeah.
是啊 年纪大了 老姑娘了
She's just a... tired old girl.
- 唉 - 撑不了多久了
- Aw. - Won't be too much longer now.
能不能麻烦您帮我看下包裹到没到？
I don't suppose you'd be able to just check to see if the package has arrived?
哦 呃...
Oh. Um...
好 我去看下
Uh, okay.
- 麻烦啦 - 请稍等
- Thank you. - You wait here.
抱歉 女士 信箱是空的
I'm sorry, ma'am. There's nothing there.
特快的 应该早到了
Well, it was sent Priority Mail. It should have already arrived.
抱歉
I'm sorry.
哦 好吧
Huh. Okay.
今天真不顺
Not a good day.
你朋友最近搬家了吗？
Did your friend recently move, by any chance?
要是搬了 系统里就有转寄地址
If they did, there would be a forwarding address on file,
包裹被转错的话就会晚到
and if it was rerouted, well, that could explain the delay.
对 有转寄
Yes. Mail forwarding.
天呐 这说得通了
Oh, my gosh. That makes total sense.
他刚搬过来
He just moved here, actually.
麻烦问一下
Can you tell me something?
旧运单号上会显示新目的地吗？
Will the new destination show up on that old tracking number?
是这样的
Now, there's the thing.
运单信息不一定更新转寄信息
Tracking does not always carry over to forwarding
那是两个不同的系统
because they're different services.
“富兰克林先生 请注意”
"This is a message for Mr. Franklin.
“贵司前员工莎拉·格兰特把一份”
We've been given a copy of a food safety assessment
“关于肥沃新月小麦项目的”
of Cybo Sementis's Fertile Crescent wheat program
“食品安全评估交给了我们”
by Sarah Grant, a former employee of yours, who has engaged our services.
“文件有311页 带两个附录”
It is 311 pages long and contains two appendices.
“只要你们无条件承诺别再骚扰她”
In exchange for your unconditional agreement to leave her alone,
“我们客户愿意归还文件”
our client would like to return this document
“并保证永不提及”
"and agree never to mention it again."
“我们客户愿意归还文件”
"Our client would like to return this document
“并保证永不提及”
and agree never to mention it again.
“与她的一切沟通由我们代表”
All communication with her must come through us.
“请在646‑167‑1573留言”
Leave a message on 646-167-1573.
“我们会告知后续安排”
"We will contact you with further instructions."
留的号码是同一个 都转到了语音信箱
Callback number is the same. Goes to the messaging service.
留言公司有戏吗
Check out the answer service HQ.
试过了 他们系统毫无漏洞
I tried that. Client protection is super tight.
喂
Hello?
大都会传呼中心
A person is calling from the Tri-State Relay Service.
您接过传呼电话吗？
Have you received a relay call before?
“你们在骚扰我们的客户莎拉·格兰特”
"You've been harassing our client, Sarah Grant.
“请立刻停止”
Please stop."
她违反保密协议 偷走了公司文件
She violated her NDA, and she's holding on to stolen research,
所以不行 请传达
so no can do. Go ahead.
“文件已在我们这里”
"And now she's given it to us.
“证明是 第九页开头写着：”
In case you're doubting this, page nine starts with:
“肥沃新月样本7中 克洛兰烯二萜的增强...”
'The enhancement of clerodane diterpenes in Fertile Crescent sample 7...'"
够了 明白了 请传达
All right. I understand. Go ahead.
“我们已给赛博育种CEO留了话”
"We've left word at the office of Cybo Sementis's CEO, Mr. Franklin.
“等富兰克林先生回复”
We await his response."
富总把你的留言转给我们了 （去查）
Mr. Franklin passed on your message. Track it.
已授权我们代表他 请传达
And he's authorized us to speak on his behalf. Go ahead.
“你是谁？什么职务？”
"Who am I speaking to, and what is your position?"
我叫史蒂夫·道森 别查了 假名
Well, my name is Steve Dawson. Don't look it up. It's not real.
我们小组负责把文件追回 请传达
And my team is tasked with returning the documents. Go ahead.
“我们愿意尽快归还”
"We wish to return them as soon as possible,"
“但为保护客户”
but in order to protect our client,
“我们随时准备”
we are ready to send them simultaneously
“将文件交给各个执法机构”
to all appropriate law-enforcement agencies
“和各大媒体”
as well as every major media outlet
“若你们不...”
if you don't fully cooperate...
- “全面配合的话” - (去你的)
- ...with our requests." - Fuck you.
我们会尽力配合 请传达
We'll do our best to cooperate. Go ahead.
“立即停止对我们客户的威胁和监视”
"There will be no more threats to our client, no surveillance,
“包括电话窃听”
including phone taps.
“确认客户安全后”
Once we are satisfied with our client's security,
“原件会归还”
we'll return the original.
“我们将保留一份副本作为保险”
"We will keep a single secure copy as insurance for our client's protection."
怎么能相信你 万一你是假冒的 请传达
How do we know to trust you? You could be anyone. Go ahead.
“你们也会是我们的客户”
"You will be our client, too."
“请支付保证金”
You will be required to pay a fee.
“我们同时为双方负责”
We work for both parties to ensure
“确保万无一失”
that the job is done with no loose ends.
“事情顺利符合大家利益”
"It is in all our interests for it to run smoothly."
真周到 费用多少？请传达
That's very kind of you. How much is the fee? Go ahead.
- “五十万美元 现金” - 这钱不少
- "Half a million dollars cash." - That's a lot of money.
怎么相信你的客户是否别有用心？请传达
How do we trust your client's intentions? Go ahead.
“你一直在窃听我们的客户”
"You were tapping our client's first calls.
“对她的意图了解得和我们一样多”
You know as much about their intentions as we do."
我得回去请示下 请传达
I'm gonna have to run it internally. Go ahead.
“必须在明天下班前确认是否接受”
"You have until end of day tomorrow to confirm your acceptance."
明白了 请传达
Yeah, understood. Go ahead.
“现在把你的车挪开 离我们客户远点”
"Now get a new parking spot and stay away from our client."
来电者已挂断
Your caller has hung up.
感谢使用大都会传呼 祝您...
Thank you for using Tri-State Relay Service. Have a wonderful...
我们走
Let's go.
“信用卡还是借记卡？”
Credit or debit?
支票
Check.
监视的大面包车走了 谢谢你
The surveillance van is gone. Thank you.
“好 现在等几天”
"Good. Now we wait for a few days."
“保持耐心 别慌”
You will need to be patient and stay calm.
“一旦他们履约”
Once they fulfill their end of the deal,
“会在下周证监会”
we'll arrange to return the documents
“敲定前把资料安排归还”
before the SEC deadline next week.
“归还后您还要找个地方避避”
After that, you will need to relocate for a while.
“最好选择公交线路旁”
Ideally, somewhere in this country you can reach
“这样那帮人就难追踪到您”
by public transportation so they can't track you.
“这些是临时保护措施 不是永久的”
"It is for your protection and shouldn't be permanent."
我明白
I understand.
请传达
Go ahead.
对了 天气变好了
Hey, um, the weather is getting better.
我能出去透透气吗？请传达
Um, is it okay if I spend some time outside? Go ahead.
“那帮人应该不会再纠缠您了”
"They should leave you alone.
“要是发现什么可疑的 立刻告诉我们”
If you see anything that worries you, let us know."
怎么联系？
How?
联系你们可不容易啊 请传达
You're not that easy to get a hold of. Go ahead.
“每晚六点给那个号码留言”
"After 6 p.m. each day, leave a message at the number you have."
“只留一个词”
Just one word.
“说「天气」就表示有事”
If something is wrong, say, 'Weather.'
“「一切安好」表示正常”
"If everything's okay, say, 'Alright.'"
「一切安好」是两个词啊 请传达
"All right" is two words, not one. Go ahead.
“听过谁人乐队吗？”
"Ever listen to The Who?
“去听下他们第一张专辑 背面第一首”
First album. First track on the B side."
来电者已挂断 感谢使用...
Your caller has hung up. Thank you for...
你经常来戒酒会 但没见过你发过言
I see you at meetings, but I've never seen you share.
戒酒多久了？
How long you sober?
十九个月
Nineteen months.
到哪一步了？
What step you on?
在第四步徘徊
I've been kicking around step four.
- 嗯 - 已经有一阵子了
- Mm-hmm. - For a minute, actually.
- 做道德自省 - 嗯
- Moral inventory? - Yeah.
列出所有记恨的事了吗？
Resentments?
有啊 写了不少
Yeah. I got a lot of those.
有工作吗？
You working?
干哪行的？
What kind of gig?
主要跑腿
Mostly delivery.
送包裹 外卖之类的
Parcels, food, stuff like that.
顺带做点别的跑腿活
I got a little something on the side, too.
正经活儿吗？
Legal?
不愿告诉我吗？
You don't wanna tell me?
有危险吗？
Dangerous?
乔恩 我们都是成瘾者
We're addicts, Jon.
会做上瘾的事
We do addicty things.
得提醒自己别把一个瘾
And we just gotta be aware of them and pull back
换成另一个 要收住
so we don't replace one addiction with a new one.
要是做的事很关键
What if what you're doing is important
而且非得有人去做 怎么办？
and somebody has to do it?
那你得分清孰轻孰重
Well, you have to decide how important.
听着 不管你面对什么
Listen, however you're managing,
别独自承受
you just don't need to do it all on your own.
终究是...
The fact is...
撑不住的
you can't.
公司同意了
They've agreed to your terms.
钱怎么给你？
How do we transfer the money?
下一步安排是什么？
What do you want us to do next?
“把无标记的现金用隔夜达寄出”
"Send unmarked cash to P.O. Box 897,
“寄到 加州兰德斯 信箱897 邮编92285”
Landers, California, 92285, overnight priority.
“确认收钱后”
When it has been safely received,
“我们再下指示”
we will issue further instructions.
“要是拖延 文件就曝光”
"Any delay and the document goes public."
来电者已挂断
Your caller has hung up.
感谢使用大都会传呼 祝您生活愉快
Thank you for using the Tri-State Relay Service. And have a wonderful day.
真不要脸
He's brazen.
来 拿好
Okay. Oh.
这玩意儿电池能撑多久？
How long do the batteries in those things last?
四五天 够用的
Four or five days. Should be enough.
- 该够吧 - 臭小子 去死吧
- Right? - Fuck you, pal.
- 装箱封好 - 幸好不是我掏钱
- Box it up. - Glad I don't have to pay it.
定位追踪已开启
The tracker is activated.
好
That's cool.
专属答录信箱
Special answering service.
信箱482 一条新留言
Inbox 482. One new message.
钱已寄出
The package has been sent.
运单号是4739-27721
Tracking number 4739-27721.
距离敲定不到一周了
The filing deadline's less than a week away,
抓紧拿钱办事吧
so ball's in your court.
一切安好
All right.
一切...安好
All... right.
（手语）- 嗨 - 嗨
（手语）你怎么这么久才来？
你懂的 忙工作 忙工作
You know what it is, man. Work, work.
（手语）要做证件是吧？
对 做个身份证
Yeah. Uh, I need an ID.
（手语）拿资料来
（手语）我看下
（手语）地址选我老家行吗？
明尼苏达吗？行 可以
Minnesota? Yeah. That's fine.
（手语）我跟你说 这活一开始简单
（手语）现在真难做
难了 是吧
Getting harder, huh?
（手语）我得花足足三天
三天？可以啊
Three days? That's cool, man.
（手语）你这活可不便宜
哦 价格高 靠 好吧
Oh, price... Oh, motherfucker. Okay.
（手语）得天价
- （手语）得大笔的钱 - 怎么了？
What?
老兄 别这样 又在忽悠我
Bro, come on, man. You always bullshitting me, bro.
（手语）没得商量
咱们老相识了
Yo, you know me.
（手语）涨钱了
什么意思？
What is it?
（手语）没办法
或者什么？
Or what?
四千美元吗？
You want four?
（手语）先付钱再干
...信箱482
...482.
一条新留言
One new message.
我是霍夫曼
This is Hoffman.
奥蒂莫制药真是骗人骗到家了
Optimo Pharmaceutical's history of fraud is incredible.
交点罚款 又继续做老一套了
They just pay the fines and keep doing the same thing.
这些谎言得害多少条人命啊？
How many people have died because of their lies?
又有多少是我害的？
Lies that I was a part of.
我连侄女的洗礼都没法去
I missed my niece's baptism.
我还会错过多少人生？
I wonder what else I'm missing.
一切...安好
All... right.
一切照旧 世界安好
All is right with the world.
开个玩笑 懂吧？
Joke, right?
很好奇你的人生是什么样的
I wonder what your life is like.
不知道你能不能听这么久
I wonder if you even listen this far in.
你孤独吗？
Are you lonely?
信箱482 暂无新留言
Inbox 482. No new messages.
喂
Yes.
大都会传呼中心
This is Tri-State Relay Service.
您接过传呼电话吗？
Have you received a relay call before?
接过 支票
Yes. Check.
抱歉今天没报平安
Sorry I didn't call.
都还好吧？请传达
Is something wrong? Go ahead.
我就想看看你是否安好
I just wanted to see if you were okay.
嗯 我没事 你呢？
Yeah. I'm fine. What about you?
你还好吧？请传达
Are you okay? Go ahead.
我也好 我听了你的留言
I'm fine. I listened to your message.
歌选得挺有意思的
Interesting musical choice.
天呐 你竟然听到最后
Oh, God. You listened to the end.
抱歉 请传达
Sorry. Go ahead.
你怎么知道那歌还有原版的？
How did you know there was an original to that song?
上网查
Google.
我会用现代技术
I use modern technology.
好像你不会
Feels like you don't.
除了谁人乐队你还听啥？请传达
So, what else do you listen to aside from The Who? Go ahead.
- 谁说我听他们的？ - 得了吧
- Who said I listened to them? - Oh, come on.
我有的是时间
I've got time on my hands.
你推荐啥我都能听 请传达
I can listen to anything you can recommend. Go ahead.
我建议咱俩还是少联系为好
I recommend we keep communication to a minimum.
好啦 既然你听完了整条留言
Well, you stuck around to listen to all of my last message.
那么你是吗？
So, are you?
请传达
Go ahead.
我是什么？
Am I what?
是否孤独
Lonely.
请传达
Go ahead.
跟一个对自己了如指掌的人聊
It's strange talking to someone who knows so much about you
而自己对TA一无所知 挺奇怪的
when you know so little about them.
我能问你个问题吗？
May I ask you a question?
请传达
Go ahead.
得看是什么问题
It depends what it is.
有没有出过差错？
Has it ever gone wrong?
请传达
Go ahead.
有人会打退堂鼓
Sometimes people run.
有时我们只能放手
Sometimes we have to walk away.
不是每个人都照指示办
The instructions, not everybody listens.
我会尽量乖的
I'll try hard to behave myself.
晚安
Good night.
是个新号码 追踪出来
That was a new number. Run it.
好家伙 关机了
Nice. It's already off.
- 好 办好了 - 谢谢
- Okay, you're all set. - Thank you.
- 你好 - 你好
- Hi. - Hi.
我在加州有个信箱
I have a mailbox in California.
平常住那儿
That's where I normally live.
但我要去欧洲出差一个月
But I'm going away to Europe for a month on business.
真倒霉
I know. Poor me.
麻烦把我所有邮件转寄到
Um, could I please have all my mail forwarded to my cousin
- 我在波基普西的亲戚 好吗？- 行 可以的
- who lives in Poughkeepsie? - Yes. That's possible.
她正要搬家 该怎么办
And she's actually moving. So, what do I do?
寄到邮局代收行不行？
Send it to General Delivery?
行 没错 她取件需要出示身份证
Yep. You got it. She'll need an ID to pick anything up.
好的 行 那就转寄 麻烦了
All right. Cool. Let's do that. Thank you.
从加州兰德斯转寄
So, it'll be coming from Landers, California.
转寄收件人姓名是？
And the name of the person it's going to?
莎拉·格兰特 草字头的莎
Sarah with an "H." Grant.
嗯
Mm-hmm.
我是道森
This is Dawson.
邮件状态显示钱已送达
According to the USPS, the money's been delivered.
距离证监会还有三天
The SEC filing is in three days,
马上把交接安排好
so we're expecting handover arrangements as soon as possible.
但有个问题
But we have a problem.
你跟CEO富总说 文件是311页
You told Mr. Franklin you had a 311-page document.
但完整报告是327页
But the full report is 327 pages
而且第三附录就有16页
with a 16-page third appendix.
每一页都要归还
We need all the pages returned.
要不然 给你五十万干嘛？
Otherwise, why did we pay half a million dollars?
时间不等人 混蛋
Tick-tock, motherfucker.
“您确认过所有文件已经完整寄出”
"You told us that you had sent all the relevant documents."
寄了 请传达
I did. Go ahead.
“第三附录呢？少了”
"What about Appendix C? It's missing."
那里没实质内容 都是小字条款
There was no info there. It was all just small print.
跟研究无关 请传达
Nothing pertaining to the research. Go ahead.
“什么把它漏掉？”
"Why would you leave it out?"
我没多想
I just didn't think.
“您手上还有吗？”
"Do you still have it?"
- 有 我还有 请传达 - “他们要那份”
- Yes, I do. Go ahead. - "They need it."
我再寄给你们 请传达
I will send it to you like before. Go ahead.
“来不及了 我们警告过您”
"Takes too long. You were warned.
“必须按指示来 不然后果自负”
You must follow the steps, or we can't protect you."
求你别撒手不管
Please don't leave me to do this by myself.
“第七大道和西四十六街 交叉口有个报刊亭”
"There's a news stand on the corner of 7th and West 46th."
“把文件信封塞到左起第二堆”
Put the envelope in the pages of the bottom copy
“最下面那份《华盛顿邮报》里面”
of The Washington Post, which is the second pile on the left.
“塞好马上离开”
"Then leave the area."
跟上
Go.
- 谢谢 - 小意思
- Thank you. - Yeah. No problem.
- 生意好吧 - 还行
- How's it going? - It's going.
老样子
Yeah?
还买点别的吗？
Just that?
能给你拍张照吗？我们在做个项目
Could I get your photo? Doing this thing on New Yorkers
记录纽约人日常生活 拍一下吧
in their natural habitat. You know what I'm saying?
拍一下吧
Come on!
照你指示 塞到最左边那堆了
I left it in the Post, bottom copy, left pile like you said.
“《华盛顿邮报》是左起第二堆”
"The Washington Post is second from the left."
左起第二堆吗
Second from the left.
真对不起
I'm so sorry.
太匆忙了 我这就去重新放
Everything happened so fast. Um, I'll come back for it.
“太迟了 你知道有人在跟踪你吗？”
"It'll be gone by then. Did you know you were being followed?"
不知道 我以为那帮人停手了
No. I thought they stopped that.
真的很抱歉 是我的错
I'm so sorry. It's my fault.
别撒手啊
Don't walk away.
今天老娘过生日 贱人
It's my birthday, bitch!
过生日 要吃糖
It's my birthday, and I'm getting candy!
老娘还要买彩票
And give me some goddamn lottery tickets, too.
放 放回去 别 该死
Put the... Put the candy... Fuck.
嘿！站住！站住！
Hey! Hey! Hey! Hey!
拿到了吗？拿到了吗？谢谢你
Did you get it? Did you get it? Thank you.
嘿！嘿 嘿！在哪？在哪儿？
Hey! Hey, hey! Where is it? Where is it?
住手 你搞什么鬼
What the fuck, man?
你把它放哪了？
Where'd you put it?
看 这就是他 装成保安
That's him right there. Security guard.
真没想到
No shit.
就是这个人
It's this guy right here.
我当时坐那儿 盯着西装男
I'm sitting there, I'm watching the guy in the fucking suit.
那混蛋就在跟前
And this bastard is right there.
对 你有印象吗？
Yeah, you remember him?
喂
Yeah.
大都会传呼中心 有人通过传呼跟您通话
A person is calling through the Tri-State Relay Service.
您接过传呼电话吗？
Have you received a call from us before?
有的 等一下
Yes, we have. Just give me one second, please.
嘿 醒醒 传呼电话
Hey, yo. Hey, hey. TTY.
在的 请传达
Yeah. I'm here. Go ahead.
“我们准备了四十套完整报告 包括附录”
"We've got 40 copies, including the missing appendix,"
“准备曝光给各家媒体”
ready to go to spread across the mainstream and alternative media.
“你们答应过不再跟踪和骚扰她”
"You agreed to stop following and harassing her."
她在时报广场
She was in Times Square
拿着那份敏感文件到处跑
with a document that contains sensitive material.
“没跟踪怎么会知道她去哪里”
You wouldn't know that if you weren't following her.
“要我们曝光吗？”
"Do you want us to go public?"
我们道歉 抱歉 我们错了
We apologize. We're sorry. We made a mistake.
今后完全照办 请传达
And we'll do exactly as you say from now on. Go ahead.
“交接由我们的客户和”
"The handover will be between our client"
“你们的CEO富兰克林当面完成”
and your CEO, Franklin, in person,
“时间是周四晚七点 地点我们定 在公共场所”
"in a public place of our choice at 7 p.m. on Thursday."
富总出差了
Mr. Franklin is out of town.
那就叫他回来
Well, get him back.
“请他回来”
"Ask him to return."
尽力安排
Oh, yeah. I'll try my best.
周四正好是证监会敲定前一天
Thursday is the day before the SEC filing.
卡得太紧 请传达
That's cutting it close. Go ahead.
“就看你们了”
"You'd better make it work."
来电者已挂断
Your caller has hung up.
感谢使用大...
Thank you for using...
- 行了 - 拍到他了
- That's it. - We got our guy.
这是他
That's him.
让政府情报中心的朋友处理这图
We'll get him to our friends at a fusion center.
跑人脸识别？不够清楚吧
For facial recognition? I don't think it's good enough.
拍到最好的就这张了
That's the best frame of his face we have.
已为您接通
Your call is now connected.
你 你还好吧？请传达
Are you all right? Go ahead.
你 你还...
Uh, are you th...
你还在吗？
Are you there?
请讲
Hello?
“文件我们已拿到  交接定在周四”
"We have it. We're setting the exchange for Thursday."
“在那之前 您每天打一次电话”
Until then, you'll call each day once
“只留一句话”
and leave a message.
“说「一切安好」或「天气」”
You'll say, 'All right, ' or you'll say, 'Weather.'
“别再多嘴”
Nothing more.
“照我们指示做”
You'll follow instructions because this time,
“否则我们就撒手 懂吗？”
"we will walk away. Do you understand?"
懂
Yes.
- 请传达 - 来电者已挂断
- Go ahead. - Your caller has hung up.
感谢使用大都会传呼
Thank you for using the Tri-State Relay Service.
祝您晚上愉快
Have a wonderful night.
你好 麻烦订个位
Hey. Um, I'd like to book a table, please.
最后地点在贝尔
We tracked it as far as Bell.
那儿是个全国物流中心
There's a national distribution center there.
之后就没信号了
Then we lost it.
信号还回得来吗？
Will the signal come back?
里头没有备用电池
There were no backup batteries.
接下来会往哪寄？
Where's it gonna go from there?
全国各地到处都有可能
It could literally be anywhere.
一切安好
All right.
我是霍夫曼
It's Hoffman.
我一直在翻那些参加了
I've been checking the obituaries of the towns
奥蒂莫试验城镇的讣告
that were part of Optimo's trials.
健康年轻人接二连三地死去
Healthy young people suddenly dying.
还有多少没被发现的？
How many more are there?
内部都明白这些试验不严谨
We all knew the trials were inadequate.
还没弄清楚前 公司就说一切安全了
They said things were safe way before we knew enough.
你知道覆盖面有多广吗
You know how widely it was distributed.
上百万人会受影响
Millions of people will have been affected,
可奥蒂莫会否认一切
but Optimo will deny it.
我本有机会揭发的 给浪费了
I had a chance to do something, and I blew it.
我手上沾满了血
I've got blood on my hands.
这不是你的错 你只是帮忙的
It's not your fault. You helped me.
谢谢你 我不会再来打扰了
Thank you. I won't bother you again.
我叫乔恩 我有酒瘾
I'm Jon, and I'm an alcoholic.
欢迎 乔恩
Hi, Jon.
我打小就是穆斯林 按规矩根本不能喝酒
Growing up Muslim, you're not supposed to drink at all.
我...
I, uh...
我作为穆斯林 在911后的纽约...
So, I grew up Muslim in New York...
长大
post 9/11.
太艰难了
It was crazy.
我以为喝酒能帮我合群
I figured drinking would help me to fit in
跟人打成一片
and just connect to people more.
确实 有一点作用
And it did, a little.
可是还是经常被人痛揍
Didn't stop me getting my ass kicked all the time.
被打的时候 喝酒能麻痹痛苦
But when that happened, it would help me go numb.
总之 酒是帮了我
So, either way, it helped.
后来去华尔街工作了
And then I got a job on Wall Street.
工作强度非常高
It was intense.
喝酒也是合群的一部分
Drinking was part of fitting in.
也用来应付那些
And it was a way of dealing
变态业绩指标的压力
with pressure to meet these crazy targets.
根本不可能完成那些指标
There was no way of meeting them.
除非违反规则
Not without bending the rules
坑害别人
and screwing people over.
我确实想融入什么
Much as I wanted to be a part of something,
但不想同流合污
I didn't wanna be a part of that.
所以我开始搜集证据
So, I started gathering information,
然后交给了我的领导们
and I took it to my superiors.
他们瞧了瞧
They took a look at it.
结果没下文了
And nothing really happened.
调查有失公允 明显包庇
The investigation was one-sided.
事一平息
It all blew over. And when it did,
那些老相识都背离我
people I had known a long time turned their backs on me,
到处传我的坏话
started spreading rumors about me.
他们开始怀疑我的头脑和人品
You know, questioning my sanity and my integrity.
我开始变得偏执 易怒
And I started to become, uh, paranoid
还喝得烂醉
and aggressive and drunk.
公司拿着保密协议和离职补偿找我时
By the time they came to me with this severance package, it was tied to an NDA.
我如释重负
I was relieved.
所以 我...
So, I, uh...
我收了那笔钱
I took the money.
我守口如瓶
I kept my mouth shut,
大口灌酒把事塞回去
poured it all down my throat.
但我对那经历满是羞愧
But I still carry a lot of guilt and shame about that time.
我老觉得自己是个懦夫
And I keep thinking I was a coward.
我确实很懦弱 是真的
And I was weak. I was.
昨晚有人打电话给我
I got a call from someone last night,
他听起来完全...崩溃...
and he just sounded so... lost...
无助
and broken.
老实说 我觉得他熬不过去了
And I don't think he's gonna make it, honestly.
我不想最后落到那样的结局
I don't wanna end up like that.
谢谢你 沃什
Thank you, Wash.
“报告的原件已经以您的名字”
"The original copy of the report is waiting under your name
“寄到了第八街邮政总局代收处”
in General Delivery at the main post office on 8th.
“用亚当·富兰克林的名字”
A table is booked for Adam Franklin
“在今晚七点北欧盖洛餐厅留好了位”
at Gaia & Loki restaurant at 7 p.m. tonight.
“坐出租去那儿 让司机等着”
Take a taxi there and make it wait.
“把报告和您收到的黄标手机带上”
Bring the report and the yellow marked phone you were sent.
“文件交给他后”
When he arrives, hand him the documents,
“拍张你们两人的合影”
take a picture of the two of you,
“回到出租车 往城北走”
get back in the taxi and head uptown.
“之后会给您下一步指示”
You will receive further instructions then.
“明白了吗？”
"Do you understand?"
明白了 请传达
Yes, I do. Go ahead.
来电者已挂断 感谢使用
Your caller has hung up. Thank you for using
大都会传呼中心 祝您生活愉快
the Tri-State Relay Service. Have a wonderful day.
“富兰克林先生必须亲自到场”
"Mr. Franklin must attend in person,
“我们的客户会要求合影”
and our client will need to take a photograph with him.
“她会把报告的原件交回”
She will return the original copy of the report,
“我们只留一份副本做保险”
and we will keep a single safety copy
“确保大家都守约”
"to ensure everyone sticks to the deal."
来电者已挂断 感谢使用
Your caller has hung up. Thank you for using
大都会传呼 祝您生活...
the Tri-State Relay Service. Have a wonderful...
还要杯水吗？
Can I get you another club soda?
暂时不用了
No. I'm good.
- 好 - 谢谢
- Okay. - Thank you.
...一条新留言
...one new message.
天气 我知道我本先该联系你
Weather. I know I should have called.
你别担心 我没事
You don't have to worry. I'm okay.
你暴露了
They know who you are.
那帮人说 时报广场的
They said facial recognition
监控识别出了你
got a positive ID of you in Times Square.
他们告诉我你叫 詹姆斯·基顿
They told me your name. James Keaton.
你现在很危险 詹姆斯 都是我连累的
You're in big danger, James. This is my fault.
你得赶快跑 别回来
You've got to get out of here and stay away.
- 不 不 不 不 不 - 我在时报广场搞砸了
- No, no, no, no, no. - I screwed up in Times Square,
所以我要亲自来交接
so I'm gonna do this handover myself.
见鬼！
Fuck!
市政礼堂有一场舒伯特音乐会
There's a concert of Schubert's Piano Trios at town hall.
公共场合 就像你教我的
It's public, like you said it should be.
该死！
Fuck!
那帮人叫我别告诉你 但我必须说
They told me not to tell you, but I needed to.
感谢你一直照顾我
And to thank you for looking after me.
再见了 詹姆斯 务必小心
Goodbye, James. Be safe.
买张票
Let me get a ticket.
请拿好
Here you are.
- 不用找零了 - 谢谢
- Keep the change. - Thank you.
等下 这是啥？
Whoa, what is that?
听力辅助器 给听障人士用的
It's a hearing-assisted device for the deaf.
好 那得去检查一下
All right. Well, you gotta check it.
是我 别怕 信用卡还是借记卡
It's me. It's me. Credit or debit.
是个圈套 那帮人要来抓你 快走
It's a trap. They're coming to get you. Come on.
借过 借过
Excuse me. Excuse me.
让开 让开 让开
Move, move, move!
把这个戴上
Put this on.
戴上这个 脱掉外套
Put this on. Take this off.
报告给他们了吗？
Did you give it to them? The report.
- 没有 - 好
- No. - Good.
得把打算曝光做的更真
Our threat to go public has to feel real.
这是你唯一的筹码
It's the only leverage you got.
坐火车去波基普西 全用现金
Take the train to Poughkeepsie. You're gonna pay in cash.
到了去格兰德酒店订房
When you get there, you go to the Grand Hotel.
用莎拉去掉草字头的写法订房
You book under your own name, but you misspell it, all right?
我得回公寓取点东西
I gotta go back to the apartment and get my stuff.
不行 不能 别回去
No, you don't. You can't.
那帮人怎么跟你联系上的？
How did they get in touch with you?
他 他们按了对讲门铃
They, uh... They rang the intercom.
有伤害你吗？
Did they hurt you?
- 没有 - 好 很好
- No. - Okay, good.
到了之后打电话报平安
When you get there, call me and let me know you're okay.
我会马上给你回...
I'm gonna call you right ba...
我们会用邮政信箱给你发信
We're gonna contact you with a P.O. Box number.
明白吗？你得记住邮箱号码
All right? You're gonna have to remember it.
你能直接告诉我吗？
Will you just tell me?
你在路上时我得保护你
I gotta protect you while you're traveling.
你去邮政总局 找一个信封
You go to the main post office, ask for an envelope.
里面是邮政信箱钥匙和指示
It's got a P.O. Box key in it and the rest of the instructions.
嘿！
Yo!
上车
Let's go.
来
Here.
去中央车站 快点
Grand Central. Let's go.
别怕
You're okay.
- 文件带了吗？ - 带了
- You got the papers? - Yeah.
现在起只用现金
From now on, it's cash only.
刷卡会被追踪
Use a card, they're gonna trace you.
拿新身份证件去邮局取件
ID. You got a new one waiting for you at the post office.
别说了 拜托停下
Stop. Please stop.
你为什么要这样帮我？
Why did you do this for me?
这是我的工作
It's my job.
做那么多吗？
Was that all?
你既符合我想象 又出乎我意料 詹姆斯
You know, you're exactly and not at all what I imagined, James.
我不叫那个
That's not my name.
他们骗了你
They lied to you.
那你叫什么？
What is your name?
叫阿什
It's Ash.
阿什拉夫
Ashraf.
阿什拉夫 我是你最麻烦的客户吗？
Am I your worst client ever, Ashraf?
也许吧
Maybe.
嘿
Hey.
你会一切安好的
You're gonna be all right.
一起走吧 阿什拉夫
Come with me, Ashraf.
我不能
I can't.
再见了
Goodbye.
穿着吧
Keep it.
别回头看
Don't look back.
“你就是你们的招数？”
"What was your plan?"
“觉得我在开玩笑？”
That I was bluffing?
“别指望再找到她”
I'll make sure you never find her.
“她消失了 我也消失了”
"She's gone and so am I."
来电者已挂断
Your caller has hung up.
感谢使用大都会传呼
Thank you for using the Tri-State Relay Service.
祝您晚...
Have a won...
谢谢
Thank you.
莎拉 不能再用这手机了
Sarah, you can't use this phone.
明白吗？抓紧扔掉
All right? You got to get rid of it right away.
总算听到你的声音了
Glad to finally hear your voice.
跟那该死的传呼都聊腻了
We're getting bored of speaking to this fucking relay service.
这小手机挺管用的 多谢你
This little phone has been very useful. Thank you.
把她抓来让你听听
I'll get her for you.
别 别照他们说的做 他 他们在跟踪我
Don't... don't do what they say. They were tracking me.
莎拉 听我说 保持冷静
Sarah, listen to me. You gotta stay calm.
- 都怪我 - 听我说
- It's my fault. - Listen to me.
会有办法的
We're gonna figure this out.
- 替我冷静一下 - 别管我了
- Just stay calm for me. - Just walk away.
手机给我
Give it here.
现在照我们的指示做 懂吗？
You're going to do what we say now. You understand?
放了她 行不？
Listen, let her go. All right?
不然所有的文件都会曝光  听见没？
The documents are going out, all of them. You hear me?
那又怎样？
And then what, huh?
指望记者或读者关心？
The idea of journalists or their readers actually caring,
可爱又幼稚的幻想
it's a cute, liberal fantasy.
多数媒体跟我们合作
Most of the media work with us anyway,
不会急着发
so they won't publish in a hurry.
只能发网上当谣言了
And that leaves the conspiracy theorists on social media.
祝好运
Good luck with that.
执法机关可是火眼金睛
Guess what. Law enforcement is gonna be reading more closely,
别想惹我 懂吗？
so don't fucking push me, all right?
信封都封好了
The envelopes are labeled and sealed.
- 懂吗？ - 规矩是这样的
- All right? - Here's the deal.
我们跟你去藏文件的地方
We're gonna come with you to wherever you keep your documents,
你把所有副本交给我们
and you're gonna give us all the copies of the report,
包括保险备份 她就能平安无事
including your safety copy, and we'll let her go unharmed.
你听话也能保住命
And you, too, if you behave yourself.
你们王八蛋想什么的？
You gotta be out your fucking mind.
我不能危及别的客户
I have other clients to consider.
你真以为你还有得选？
You really think you have a choice?
说
Yeah?
行 我照办
Yeah, I'll do it.
带你们去拿所有档案
I'll take you to all the records. I'll do it.
好 很好
That's good. That's very good.
明早天一亮 到你客户的公寓来
Dawn tomorrow, you come to your client's apartment.
莎拉 你还好吧？
Sarah, you okay?
我还好
I'm fine.
文件在哪？
Where's the documents?
你放了她 我就说
You let her go, I'll tell you.
别打了
Stop.
想拿文件就得让我们俩都活着
You want the documents, you need us both alive.
先放了她 我们好好谈
So, why don't you let her go, and we'll talk.
用不着她
Don't really need her.
嘿 别冲动！
Hey! Easy.
- 别冲动！ - 文件到底在哪儿？
- Hey! - Where are the documents?
纽瓦克南第二街10001号
10001 South Second Street, Newark.
去纽瓦克 南第二街10001号
Newark. 10001 South Second Street.
他挺喜欢你的
He likes you.
你个小崽子
Oh, you motherfucker!
你这个混蛋
Oh, you motherfucker.
行了
Stop.
干得好 老大
Good job, boss.
你们到底想要什么？
What do you want?
想要你手上的奥蒂莫制药报告副本
We want your copy of the Optimo Pharmaceutical report.
对 实际是霍夫曼那摊儿事
Yeah. This is about Hoffman.
来 来 来
Here, here. Here.
开门吧 抓紧
Unlock it. Okay, come on.
抓紧
Come on.
这门是吧？来开
This one? Come here.
抓紧
Come on.
来吧
从这里开？说什么？
This? Huh? What?
把我手松开 我才能伸手开门
You got to untie my hands so I can reach it.
脚也要解开 我进去后还有两处警报要关
Legs, too. I got two more alarms to turn off when I get in.
我会割开绳子 你要是敢再捅我
I'll cut them. You stabbed me in the motherfucking leg.
信我 我会把这刀捅进你肋骨
I'll put this in your fucking ribs, trust me.
抓紧去开
Come on, get to it.
该死！
Fuck!
等下 我得集中注意力
Give me a sec. I just gotta concentrate, okay?
抓紧 抓紧
Get to it. Come on.
怎么没反应啊
Nothing's happening.
我要毙了他
I'm gonna fucking shoot him.
这什么鬼玩意儿？站住！
What the fuck is that? Hey!
给把我枪
I need a gun.
抓活的 得要出密码
Don't kill him. We need the code.
他正在穿过铁轨 快追！
He's crossing the tracks. Go!
他就在这儿！
He's over here!
跟紧他 别让他跑了
Stay with him. Hold him!
把密码交出来 我就放你走
Give me the code, and I'll let you go.
我会开枪的
I'll do it.
开吧
Do it.
完了
No.
举起手来！
Put your hands up!
把手举高
Hands where I can see them.
好 待着别动
Okay, stay right there.
保持冷静 冷静点
Stay calm. Stay calm.
把手亮出来！
Let me see your hands!
- 轻点儿 好吗？ - 闭嘴
- Easy, okay? - Shut up!
走 上车 快点
Come on. In the car. Come on.
这是闹哪出啊？
What is this?
我有一堆文件 能证明奥蒂莫的药
I got documents that show Optimo Pharmaceutical's products
有不良反应 他们明明知情
have adverse effects, and they knew about it.
还故意掩盖
They tried to cover up the evidence.
我有内部备忘录
I got the internal memos.
邮件
I got the e-mails.
什么证据都有
I got everything.
你怎么会有这些？
Why do you have it?
这就是我的工作 帮那些看到这种事的人
This is what I do. I help people who find things like this.
那些看到不该看
Who see things maybe they shouldn't have,
却没法再装作没看见的人
who should have looked the other way, but they can't.
我得把这些交给我信得过的人
Now I gotta turn it over to somebody I trust.
嗯
Yeah.
给 有点重
It's a little heavy there.
- 谢谢 - 好
- Thank you. - Okay.